All right. So before we talk about
在讨论构建工具及其用途 以及更多细节之前
we're going to take a step back and talk about why we even need them.
先退后一步 讨论一下为什么我们会需要构建工具?
As a front-end developer,
作为一名前端开发者
you have a ton of
你总是需要管理各种库和技术
You might not have gotten a good picture for that yet.
你可能尚未对此有明确的认知
Sometimes when we're just building CSS and HTML, smaller apps,
当我们仅仅构建 CSS 和 HTML 或者较小的应用时
we just have one CSS file and one JavaScript file,
只有一个 CSS 文件和一个 JavaScript 文件
and we put everything into those two files.
会将所有内容都放在这两个文件中
But on a professional scale,
但是 在构建专业级应用时
those strategies don't work anymore.
这种方案不再可行
Because professional websites require so many assets,
因为专业网站需要大量资源
and so many different technologies to be used all the time,
并且应用很多不同的技术
it gets really hard to manage because,
资源管理将变得非常复杂
we actually have to decide at what time all of those libraries are going to run.
我们需要决定在什么时候运行什么库
We can't just throw everything onto the page and hope that it all runs at the right time.
不能只是将所有内容都放到页面上 希望它们能在正确的时间运行
So just as an example of one professional website,
因此 以一个专业网站为例
I thought we would go to the Udacity site.
可以看看优达学城的网站
Once you come to this web page,
打开网站后
you can take a look at the head tag to see
可以看一下 head 标签里面的内容
all of the assets that are being loaded onto this page,
这个页面加载的所有资源
and there's quite a lot.
数量是十分惊人的
This view, it works,
这样来看资源是可行的
but it's not really the best view.
但还不是最好的视图
If I was going to look at the assets on a web page,
如果我要查看网站加载的资源文件
I would actually navigate to the network tab.
我会切换到 Network 面板
If you haven't used it before, this is awesome.
如果你以前从未使用过 你会发现这简直太棒了
The Network tab will show you all of the assets on a page,
Network 面板会显示当前页面加载的所有资源文件
you might have to refresh it,
可能需要刷新一下
and you'll be able to see all of the different JavaScript,
然后 就能看到所有不同的 JavaScript、
CSS, and other assets being loaded onto the page.
CSS 和其它加载到页面的资源文件
So let's come here.
我们不妨尝试一下
When you scroll through these,
当你滚动浏览这些内容
you can get a ton of information about all of the different assets that are on the page.
能看到页面上不同资源的大量相关信息
So not only can I see how many bytes it's taking up,
不仅可以看到占用了多少字节
or the size of the asset,
或资源文件的大小
I can also see what type it is,
还可以看到资源类型
and I can see whether it loaded correctly or not.
以及是否正确加载
This makes the Network tab a fantastic debugging tool,
这也使 Network 选项成为一个出色的调试工具
and I highly recommend that you go to other websites and just try this out.
强烈建议你访问其他网站 亲自尝试一下
But, for right now,
但是 就目前而言
the thing that I want you to come away with is just how many assets are on this page,
我希望你能了解到 这个页面加载的资源有很多
it's just one page,
即使是一个页面 仍然运行了非常多不同的资源
We have JavaScripts, and we have gifs,
有 JavaScript 还有 gif、JPEG
and all of these other things that we need to manage.
以及需要管理的所有其它资源
Order does often matter for these as well.
另外 资源文件的顺序通常也很重要
So you can see that if a front-end developer on
因此 你可以看到 如果专业项目的前端开发者
a professional project didn't have some tool to manage all of these assets for them,
没有某种工具来帮他们管理这些资源
they might spend a lot of time just making
仅仅是确保所有资源正确地加载
sure that all of these assets load the correct way.
就会花费大量的时间
Sometimes when I'm thinking about my front-end apps,
有时候 我会把前端项目开发视作指挥一个乐团
It might sound funny,
可能听起来有点搞笑
but there are a lot of different instruments playing at anytime.
任何时候都有很多不同的乐器在演奏
If each of our web assets are like one of those instruments,
如果把每个 Web 资源都比作其中一部乐器
then the front-end developer is like the orchestra conductor.
那么 前端开发者就像这个乐团的总指挥
We have to make sure that every instrument is playing at exactly the right time,
必须确保每种乐器都在正确的时间演奏
and if even one instrument is off,
即使只是其中一部乐器没有跟上
it can throw the whole piece into not a great state.
都将影响到整个作品的演奏效果
So when you are building your front-end apps,
因此 在构建前端应用程序时
you have to think about yourself as just orchestrating all of these different assets
你需要自己编排所有不同类型的资源文件
to build the beautiful picture that we actually want the web page to be.
来构建我们所希望网页呈现的美丽画卷
The hardest part is that you as the developer won't even be there when the app runs.
最困难的是 作为开发者的你 却不能出现在应用运行的现场
It's going to run for the user.
用户自己会启动应用
So it's not just orchestrating everything at runtime,
所以 还不仅是在运行时的编排
you actually have to anticipate the order that all of these things are going to run in,
实际上你必须提前安排好所有资源的执行顺序
and record those rules for later.
记录这些规则以备后用
So it's like being an orchestra conductor in another room.
这就好像在另一个房间里当乐队指挥一样
Which is hard, and I think that's one of the hard things about front-end development.
这很难 我认为这是前端开发的难点之一
So tools like Webpack and other build tools are really going to be your friend when it
因此 要使开发流程保持简单有效 Webpack 或其他构建工具必不可少